Okay, in the last video I told you that
if you could um take those three steps
and count, then you could do a for loop.
So, let's just talk about how to do a
for loop. It comes in three steps. Um
you start by saying the word for. So,
you'll say four and then you put
parenthesis and then inside these
parentheses, the first thing you give it
is where you want it to start. Usually,
people use a variable here. saw um I'm
going to say let
counter
equal uh let's say the first example I
said is we'd start at one and go to 10.
So we'd say let counter equal one and
then you put a semicolon. Then after
that you tell it. So this says where do
you want to start counting and we're
saying start it at one. The next portion
right here is how long you want it to
count to. So when I told you to count to
10, I said start at one, go to 10. So if
we want to go to 10, we would say
counter is less than or equal to 10. So
as long as counter is less than 10, this
loop will keep going. As soon as it's
equal to 10, then the loop will stop. So
it says um so if it hits 11, 11 is not
less than 10 and the loop will stop. So
just like you did with the counting um
in your head, you're telling the
computer where to start and how long to
go.
Well, the computer doesn't automatically
know which direction to go. So, we want
to tell it to take the counter and then
for each step, each time this loop goes
through, we want the counter to go up
by one. So, we could say counter equals
counter + one. And some of you who have
programmed before may know there's some
shorter syntax for this. We'll get to
that in a minute. I just want to
demonstrate this as simply as possible.
So this for loop says give me a counter
start it at one. So start counting at
one go to 10 go up by one each time and
then anything that you put directly
after the for loop will run that many
times. So, I could say, "Let's alert the
counter."
And we'll save this. And we'll go over
here to our running code. And it says 1,
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10. Okay. So,
three parts of a for loop. Where do you
want to start? How long do you want to
run? How much do you want to count by?
And then um we'll pick up in the next